Marcel Breuer Papers
Marcel Breuer Papers
- Project Records, 1922-1982 (inclusive); 1940-1980 (bulk); 89 linear feet of manuscript material, 24,618 drawings, 6,160 photographs and slides.
  - ANNUCIATION PRIORY OF THE SISTERS OF ST. BENEDICT, PHASE II, Bismark, ND (1961-1963) [Religious]
    - Drawings, 76
      - Preliminary Room Plan, [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1175)
      - Chapel Furniture - SK-F25 (12 October 1962), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1175)
      - Construction "SK-F" Series: SK-F1 - Sk-F26 (20 March 1962-29 October 1962), [Working Drawings]; 26; (originals) (Tube 1175)
      - Construction "F" Series: F1-F6 (19 July 1961-30 April 1962), [Working Drawings]; 6; (originals) (Tube 1175)
    - Photographs, 441
      - Construction progress with annotations on reverse ( June to July, 1961), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 18 (Box 136, Folder 2)
      - Construction progress with annotations on reverse ( August 1961), construction, exterior view; (color photographs) 6 (Box 136, Folder 2)
      - Construction progress with annotations on reverse ( August 1961), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 38 (Box 136, Folder 2)
      - Construction progress with annotations on reverse ( September 1961), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 38 (Box 136, Folder 2)
      - Construction progress with annotations on reverse (October 1961), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 23 (Box 136, Folder 2)
      - Construction progress with annotations on reverse (November 1961), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 23 (Box 136, Folder 2)
      - Construction progress with annotations on reverse (December 1961), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 23 (Box 136, Folder 2)
      - Construction progress with annotations on reverse(January to February, 1962), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 36 (Box 136, Folder 3)
      - Construction progress with annotations on reverse (March 1962), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 27 (Box 136, Folder 3)
      - Construction progress with annotations on reverse (April 1962), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 26 (Box 136, Folder 3)
      - Construction progress with annotations on reverse - large format ( April 1962), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 9 (Box 136, Folder 3)
      - Construction progress with annotations on reverse (May 1962), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 21 (Box 136, Folder 3)
      - Construction progress with annotations on reverse (June 1962), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 38 (Box 136, Folder 3)
      - Construction progress with annotations on reverse (July 1962), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 35 (Box 136, Folder 3)
      - Construction progress with annotations on reverse (August 1962), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 22 (Box 136, Folder 3)
      - Construction progress with annotations on reverse (September to December, 1962), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 21 (Box 136, Folder 3)
      - Construction progress with annotations on reverse 9January to April, 1963), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 26 (Box 136, Folder 3)
      - Views of priory and bell tower, finished project, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 11 (Box 136, Folder 3)
  - APARTMENT FOR A GYMNASTICS TEACHER, Berlin, Germany (1930) [Interior], (Alternate names: Wohnung eine gymnastik lehrerin)
    - Drawings, 1
      - Grundriss (Nr. 313) [Leaf 260] (11 Feb 1930), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 2)
    - Published Material
      - Desk and chair Tachblatt fur Holzarbeiter (Apr 1931), 1 clipping; (magazine clippings ) (Oversize 19, Folder 10)
      - Tubular Steel Chair and Wooden Desk (Desk for a Gymnastics teacher) (Oversize 19, Folder 12)
      - Stahlmöbel in der Wohnung Die Baugilde (September 1930), 2045; (tear sheet) (Oversize 20, Folder 28)
      - Desk and window Die Form (Feb 1930), 1 clippingping; (magazine clippings ) (Oversize 20, Folder 32)
    - Photographs, 4
      - Studio with living area in background, finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 119, Folder 1)
      - Living area [Slide 663], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-1)
      - Studio/Living Room with Phonograph (Berlin, 1930) [Slide 394], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-1)
      - Tubular Steel Chair and Wooden Desk (Desk for a Gymnastics teacher) [Slide 684], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-1)
  - APARTMENT HOTEL ([1928-1930]) (not built) [Residential, Multi], (Alternate names: Wohn Hotel)
    - Drawings, 1
      - Appartement eines Wohnhotels (Nr. 263) [Leaf 220] (7 Nov 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 2)
    - Project Files
    - Published Material
    - Photographs, 4
      - Aerial Perspective View with Overlayed Plan., drawings, perspective rendering; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 124, Folder 9)
      - Aerial Perspective View with Overlayed Plan. [Slide 400], drawings, perspective rendering; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-1)
      - Aerial Perspective View with Overlayed Plan. [Slide 425], drawings, perspective rendering; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-1)
      - Aerial Perspective View with Overlayed Plan., drawings, perspective rendering; (glass-plate negative) 1 (Box SL-12, Folder 7)
  - APARTMENT HOUSE, NEW YORK, New York, NY (1944-1946) (not built) [Residential, Multi], (Alternate names: New York Apartment House/Kaufmann Apts./Sutton Place/East Side Apts.)
    - Drawings, 50
      - Plans, Section and Perspective Rendering [board mounted], [Presentation Drawings]; 2; (reproductions) (Oversize 14, Folder 1)
      - Perspective Rendering., [Presentation Drawings]; 2; (reproductions) (Oversize 14, Folder 1)
      - Aerial Perspective Rendering. (Artist unknown, n.d.) [Ink rendering on illustration board, 20 x 30 in.], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Map-case 112, Folder 10)
      - Sketches and Design Development Drawings. Elevations, Sections and Plans., [Design Development Drawings]; 29; (originals) (Tube 663)
      - Preliminary Study for Computations Only. Plans [original and blueprint], [Design Development Drawings]; 2; (mixed) (Tube 663)
      - Building Floor Plans, Apartment Floor Plans, Site plans and Building Section Drawing., [Design Development Drawings]; 13; (originals) (Tube 663)
      - Perspective Drawing., [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 663)
    - Project Files
      - Correspondence (Aug 1944-Jan 1946), primarily with Edgar Kaufmann, Sr./Edgar Kaufmann, Jr. (Box 112, Folder 1)
      - Report, Comparison of Rents and Cost Computations (Oct 1944-Jun 1946) (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - Published Material
    - Photographs, 2
      - Perspective Rendering of Multistory u-Shaped Building. [Slide 262], drawings, perspective rendering; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-1)
      - Unit Plans, Floor Plan, Section. [Slide 357], drawings, multiple drawings; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-1)
  - APARTMENT HOUSE, PROJECT FOR BERT GELLER, Lawrence, NY (1945) (not built) [Residential, Multi]
    - Drawings, 3
      - Sketches., [Design Development Drawings]; 3; (originals) (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - Project Files
      - Correspondence, Cost Computations and Sketches, Bert Geller (Box 112, Folder 3)
  - APARTMENT-HOUSE COMPLEX, COMPETITION, SPANDAU-HASELHORST, Berlin, Germany (1930-1931) (not built) [Residential, Multi], (Alternate names: Spandau-Haselhorst Apartments)
    - Published Material
      - Beiträge zur Frage des Hochhauses Die Form (March 1930), 113-117; (magazine clippings ) (Oversize 19, Folder 7)
      - Perspective, (magazine clippings ) (Oversize 19, Folder 17)
      - Aerial view and elevation Bauwelt (1931), 29; (tear sheet) (Oversize 19, Folder 23)
    - Photographs, 4
      - Two Exterior Perspective Views. "Multistory unites mixed with one family row houses"., drawings, perspective rendering; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 119, Folder 2)
      - Site plan and elevation., drawings, multiple drawings; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 119, Folder 2)
      - Housing scheme/plans and building section., drawings, multiple drawings; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 119, Folder 2)
      - Two Exterior Perspective Views [Slide 391], drawings, perspective rendering; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box SL-1)
  - ARISTON CLUB, Mar del Plata, Argentina (1947-1948) [Recreational]
    - Published Material
      - A Beach Club to Sell a View Architectural Record (Jul 1948), 136-139; (tear sheet) (Box 112, Folder 23)
    - Photographs, 21
      - Exterior view, construction; (black and white photographs) 12 (Box 112, Folder 5)
      - "for Arts and architecture", finished project, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 112, Folder 5)
      - "for Arts and Architecture", finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 7 (Box 112, Folder 5)
      - Partial elevation., finished project, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - ARMSTRONG RUBBER COMPANY, HEADQUARTERS, West Haven, CT (1968-1970) [Commercial]
    - Drawings, 162
      - Perspective rendering [façade pattern 1] (Lutz, n.d.) [oil on illustration board in matte frame, 30 x 36 in.], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Map-case 119, Folder 2)
      - Perspective rendering [façade pattern 2] (Lutz, n.d.) [oil on illustration board in matte frame, 30 x 36 in.], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Map-case 119, Folder 3)
      - Perspective rendering [façade pattern 2] (n.d.) [mounted color photograph of Lutz rendering, 16 x 20 in.], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Map-case 119, Folder 1)
      - Presentation Set [Jan 1967]: Perspective Rendering, Site Plan (Sheet No. 1), 1st and 2nd Floor Plans (Sheet No. 2), 5th-9th Floor Plans (Sheet No. 3), East Elevation (Sheet No. 4), South Elevation (Sheet No. 5), [Presentation Drawings]; 6; (originals) (Tube 1185)
      - Site work: Survey and topographic maps, [Design Development Drawings]; 10; (reproductions) (Tube 1185)
      - Occupancy and Egress Data [4 Aug 1967] ("as submitted to building department"): Dwg. Nos. SK 11, 11A, 12, 26, 46, 31, 33, [Working Drawings]; 7; (reproductions) (Tube 1185)
      - Misc. prints: SK-A-2, 4-6; C-SK-5, [Working Drawings]; 5; (reproductions) (Tube 1185)
      - Presentation Set [Apr 1967]: Site Plan (Sheet No. 1), 1st and 2nd Floor Plans (Sheet No. 2), 5th-9th Floor Plans (Sheet No. 3), East Elevation (Sheet No. 4), South Elevation (Sheet No. 5), [Presentation Drawings]; 5; (originals) (Tube 1185)
      - Design Development Drawings [Jun 1967-Feb 1969]: C-SK Drawings, SK Drawings and misc. unnumbered sheets, [Design Development Drawings]; 31; (originals) (Tube 1185)
      - Bid Sheets [5 Jan 1968], [Presentation Drawings]; 2; (originals) (Tube 1185)
      - Boring Location Plan [18 Aug 1967] (Sheet No. B1), [Working Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1186)
      - Boring Location Plan [11 Dec 1967] (Sheet No. B1), [Working Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1186)
      - Boring Log Data [31 Oct 1967] (Sheets 1-3), [Working Drawings]; 3; (reproductions) (Tube 1186)
      - Construction Set [20 Nov 1967] ("chronoflex originals"): Architectural (Dwg. Nos. A0-A18, A20-A32), [Working Drawings]; 39; (originals) (Tube 1186)
      - Construction Set [20 Nov 1967] ("chronoflex originals"): Structural (Dwg. Nos. S1A-S12), [Working Drawings]; 12; (originals) (Tube 1187)
      - Construction Set [20 Nov 1967] ("chronoflex originals"): Plumbing (P1-P7), HVAC (HVAC1-HVAC10), Electrical (E1-E15), Mechanical (ME1-ME2), Sprinkler (SP-1), [Working Drawings]; 37; (originals) (Tube 1188)
    - Photographs, 85
      - Construction progress photos (1968-1969), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 59 (Box 129, Folder 1)
      - Problems with concrete, some annotated (1968-1970), construction, detail; (black and white photographs) 15 (Box 129, Folder 2)
      - Exterior view, finished project; (color photographs) 3 (Box 129, Folder 3)
      - Near completion, construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 8 (Box 129, Folder 3)
  - ATLANTA CENTRAL PUBLIC LIBRARY, Atlanta, GA (1977-1980) [Library]
    - Drawings, 416
      - Facsimile of DR-118:6, [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Map-case 118, Folder 4)
      - Perspective of Entry Plaza (Artist Unknown, n.d.) [graphite on illustration board, 19 x 22 in], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Map-case 118, Folder 5)
      - Perspective from Street (Larry Perron, n.d.) [graphite on illustration board, 15.5 x 20 in], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Map-case 118, Folder 6)
      - Rough sketches and studies: plans, elevations, sections [Dec 1970-Jan 1971, undated], [Design Development Drawings]; 120; (originals) (Tube 1189)
      - Elevation Studies [n.d.], [Design Development Drawings]; 2; (originals) (Tube 1189)
      - Atlanta Library Elevations (Dwg. No. SK-1) [n.d.], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1189)
      - Building Elevations (Dwg. No. 9) [30 Jul 1976], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1189)
      - Perspective Rendering: Entrance Plaza (from plaza level). [n.d.] [ink and graphite on tracing paper], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1190)
      - Service Area Diagram [11 Nov 1971], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1190)
      - Rendered Elevations [n.d.], [Design Development Drawings]; 2; (originals) (Tube 1190)
      - Draft Elevation [n.d.], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1190)
      - Site Plan [3 Nov 1971], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1190)
      - Functional Diagrams (Service Areas) [n.d.] (with color), [Presentation Drawings]; 5; (originals) (Tube 1190)
      - Site Plan [9 Nov 1971], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1190)
      - Schematic Roof Plan [17 Nov 1971], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1190)
      - Schematic Sections and Elevations [17 Nov 1971] [original and print], [Presentation Drawings]; 2; (mixed) (Tube 1190)
      - Schematic Site Plan: Bank Building [17 Nov 1971] [original and print], [Presentation Drawings]; 2; (mixed) (Tube 1190)
      - Schematic Plans and Sections [10 Nov 1971] [original and print], [Presentation Drawings]; 2; (mixed) (Tube 1190)
      - Schematic Plan for Model [17 Nov 1971] [original and print], [Presentation Drawings]; 2; (mixed) (Tube 1190)
      - Alternate Site Schemes (with color) [n.d.], [Presentation Drawings]; 5; (reproductions) (Tube 1190)
      - Site Feasability Study for Five Points Area (Dwg. No. 1-2) [Dec 1971], [Presentation Drawings]; 2; (reproductions) (Tube 1190)
      - Trust Company of Georgia (architects: Carson, Lundin and Shaw): Plot Plan and Elevations. [c. 1970], [Other Drawings]; 4; (reproductions) (Tube 1190)
      - Site Survey (2 copies), [Site Surveys]; 2; (reproductions) (Tube 1190)
      - Large format film negatives (for Site Feasability Study presentation set), [Presentation Drawings]; 4; (reproductions) (Tube 1190)
      - Plans, Elevations and Sections [n.d.] (original set and annotated print set), [Presentation Drawings]; 26; (mixed) (Tube 1191)
      - TWFB-Atlanta, Georgia (architect: I.M. Pei and Partners): Site Plan [c. 1970], [Site Surveys]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1191)
      - Presentation Set: Ground Floor Plan, Upper Floor Plan and Rendered Elevations (Dwg. No. 2-3) [n.d.], [Presentation Drawings]; 2; (reproductions) (Tube 1191)
      - Presentation Sheets: Basement Plan, 3rd Floor Plan and 6th Floor Plan, [Presentation Drawings]; 3; (reproductions) (Tube 1191)
      - Presentation Set: Site Plan, Plans, Elevations, Sections (cover sheet and Dwgs. No. 1-4), [Presentation Drawings]; 5; (reproductions) (Tube 1191)
      - Film negatives, typed sheets and misc. material used for making of presentation set, [Presentation Drawings]; 12; (reproductions) (Tube 1191)
      - Design Development Set (preliminary working drawings) [28 Dec 1976]: Site work, plans, sections, interior and exterior elevations, etc. (Dwg. Nos. 01-02, 1-8, 10-16,18R, 20-28, 38-40), [Design Development Drawings]; 30; (originals) (Tube 1192)
      - Design Development Set (preliminary working drawings) [28 Dec 1976]: Site work, plans, sections, interior and exterior elevations, etc. (Dwg. Nos. 41-90), [Design Development Drawings]; 50; (originals) (Tube 1193)
      - Design Development Set (preliminary working drawings) [28 Dec 1976]: Site work, plans, sections, interior and exterior elevations, etc. (Dwg. Nos. 91, 93-108), [Design Development Drawings]; 17; (originals) (Tube 1194)
      - Design Development Set: Sun Study [28 Dec 1976] (Dwg. Nos. SS1-SS4 ), [Design Development Drawings]; 4; (originals) (Tube 1194)
      - Design Development Set: Precast Panels Only [Dec 1976-Feb 1977] (Dwg. Nos. 01P, 1P-6P) (annotated), [Design Development Drawings]; 7; (reproductions) (Tube 1194)
      - Egress Diagrams (3 sets, including record prints) [Aug-Oct 1976] (Dwg. Nos. 01-02, 1-6) (some with annotations), [Design Development Drawings]; 23; (reproductions) (Tube 1194)
      - Misc. construction details (including SK drawings) [Mar 1978-Feb 1980], [Working Drawings]; 9; (originals) (Tube 1195)
      - Sections Through Concrete Walls and Granite Steps [25 Sep 1979], [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1195)
      - Gift Shop [23 May 1979] (Dwg. Nos.1-2) "issued for pricing", [Working Drawings]; 2; (originals) (Tube 1195)
      - Library Gift Shop [23 Feb 1979]: Floor Plan, Wall Sections and Interior Elevations (Dwg. Nos.1-5) (Rich's Store Planning), [Consultant Drawings]; 5; (reproductions) (Tube 1195)
      - Drawer at Drive-in Window [25 Jul 1979] (S and W), [Consultant Drawings]; 2; (reproductions) (Tube 1195)
      - Channel Wall (various wall sections and details) (annotated), [Design Development Drawings]; 12; (reproductions) (Tube 1195)
      - Floor Plans (2 sets of prints, 1 with annotations), [Design Development Drawings]; 16; (reproductions) (Tube 1195)
      - Drive-in Drawer Construction Details [22 Aug 1979] (S and W) (annotated), [Consultant Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1195)
      - Annotated Survey [Oct 1970] and Site Plan revisions (annotated), [Design Development Drawings]; 4; (reproductions) (Tube 1195)
      - Revised Forecourt and Forsyth Street Gradients [Sep-Oct 1979] (1 set of originals, 2 sets of prints), [Working Drawings]; 6; (mixed) (Tube 1195)
      - Wall Panels at Gift Shop [Feb-Apr 1980] (Dwg. Nos. 37 and 37A) (Nelson and Smith), [Consultant Drawings]; 2; (reproductions) (Tube 1195)
      - Car Study at Drive-in Window [27 Jan 1977], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1195)
      - Design Development Set: 7th Floor Reflected Ceiling Plan [20 Apr 1979] (Dwg. No. 7) (annotated), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1195)
      - Design Development Set: Issued for Bookstack Only [19 May 1977] (Dwg. Nos. 01, 1-6) (annotated), [Design Development Drawings]; 7; (reproductions) (Tube 1195)
      - Misc. duplicate prints, [Design Development Drawings]; 2; (reproductions) (Tube 1195)
  - AUFRICHT HOUSE, ADDITION, Mamaroneck, NY (1953) [Residential, Single]
    - Drawings, 25
      - Plans and Rendered Elevations of Multiple Schemes; Draft Details, [Design Development Drawings]; 12; (originals) (Tube 1070)
      - Plans, Sections, Elevations, Details, [Working Drawings]; 9; (originals) (Tube 1070)
      - Electrical Layout, [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1070)
      - Plans and Elevations, [Working Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1070)
      - Air Conditioning Layout, [Working Drawings]; 2; (reproductions) (Tube 1070)
  - AUSTRALIAN EMBASSY, Paris, France (1973-1975) [Government]
    - Project Files
      - Office Correspondence (1974-1975), Correspondence between Breuer's NY and Paris office (Box 132, Folder 1)
    - Published Material
    - Photographs, 29
      - Excavation work (14 March 1975, sent by G. McDonald to T. Papachristou), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 6 (Box 132, Folder 2)
      - Foundation work (Photo-Lomprez), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 4 (Box 132, Folder 2)
      - Entrance, construction, detail; (black and white photographs) 4 (Box 132, Folder 2)
      - Scrapbook montage of construction progress (3 sheets), construction, detail; (black and white photographs) 9 (Box 132, Folder 2)
      - Excavation and foundation work, construction, exterior view; (color photographs) 6 (Box 132, Folder 2)
  - B.B. CHEMICAL COMPANY, Boston, MA (1937-1938) [Interior]
    - Project Files
      - Correspondence, sketches and invoices (Dec 1937-Nov 1938) (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - BALTIMORE GARDEN APARTMENTS, Baltimore, MD (1953-1954) (not built) [Residential, Multi]
    - Drawings, 86
      - Topographical maps and surveys., [Site Surveys]; 12; (reproductions) (Tube 578)
      - Preliminary site development, schemes 1-5. Plans, sketches and revisions., [Design Development Drawings]; 18; (mixed) (Tube 578)
      - Building sketches and tracings: elevations, plans, prespective sketches., [Design Development Drawings]; 24; (originals) (Tube 578)
      - Preliminary building schemes (23 Nov 1953), [Design Development Drawings]; 18; (mixed) (Tube 578)
      - Proposed Site Layout and Building Types A-C (5 Apr - 12 Apr 1954), [Presentation Drawings]; 6; (mixed) (Tube 578)
      - Preliminary Presentations (20 Apr 1954). Site Plan and Building Types A-C. Plans, Sections, elevations. [original + copy w/red pencil marks/edits], [Presentation Drawings]; 8; (mixed) (Tube 578)
    - Project Files
      - Correspondence, program description and project analysis (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - BAMBOS HOUSES, TYPES 1, 2 AND 3 (1927) (not built) [Residential, Single], (Alternate names: Young Master Houses)
    BAMBOS = Bayer, Albers, Meyer, Breuer, Otto, Schmidt
    - Project Files
    - Published Material
    - Photographs, 5
      - BAMBOS Type 2. Axonometric and Sections., drawings, multiple drawings; (photostat) 1 (Box 119, Folder 3)
      - BAMBOS Type 1. Ground Plan., drawings, plan; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 119, Folder 3)
      - BAMBOS Type 1. Perspective., drawings, perspective rendering; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 119, Folder 3)
      - BAMBOS Type 1. Plans, Sections, Isometric, Perspective [Slide 418], drawings, multiple drawings; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-1)
      - BAMBOS Type 1. Plan and Section. [Slide 381], drawings, multiple drawings; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-1)
  - BANDLER HOUSE, Cambridge, MA (1946) (not built) [Residential, Single]
    - Drawings, 7
      - Plans, Elevations, Details, [Working Drawings]; 3; (originals) (Tube 641)
      - Dimension Studies: Larger Dimensioned Drawings of Individual Rooms, [Design Development Drawings]; 4; (originals) (Tube 641)
    - Project Files
      - Correspondence, contracts and architect's invoice (Feb 1946-Jul 1946) (Box 112, Folder 6)
  - BANTAM ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, Bantam, CT (1954-1956) [Educational]
    - Drawings, 44
      - Photostat of Presentation Sheet: Site Plan, Floor Plan, Section, Two Elevations, [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 187)
      - Presentation Sheet in Ink on Coated Woven Medium: Site Plan, Floor Plan, Section, Four Elevations, [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 187)